# **QI CHEN**

DATA ENGINEER

### **EDUCATION**

# BS of Computer Science, Dean's List

University of Memphis/TN/2011 - 2015

## **Platform by Per Scholas**

Specialized IT Training / NY/ 2019

Furthered understanding of Big Data and Hadoop technologies. Learned how to extract, scrub, and manipulate real-time and warehouse data using SQL & Java.

## **SKILLS**

Java	
Python	
C++	
MySQL	
Hive	
Sqoop	
Oozie	
AWS	
VMWare	
MapReduce	
Hadoop	
Linux	
API	
REST	
Pandas	

## **REFERENCES**

## **Richard Duchin**

CEO & Co-founder / Vurteau

**W:** 973-618-6444 **E:** rich@vurteau.com

### John-Paul Wenger

Technical Support Lead / Dahua Technology

**W:** 562-704-6533 **C:** 562-646-6667 **E:** jp.wenger@dahuatech.com

C.	646-598-1337	$\searrow$	qchen125@gmail.com
()	github.com/swordwielder	in	linkedin.com/in/qifchen

#### **PROFILE**

Data and Analytics specialist with experience in Advertising and surveillance security industry in tech roles with focus in Data Modeling, Scheduling, Big Data, and Data Distribution. Hold a BS Degree in Computer Science with 5+ years of programming and 10 years of customer service experience utilizing software from Google Analytics

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### INDEPENDENT DEVELOPER

Freelance / New York, NY / 2019

- $\cdot$  Created a Discord bot that gives live weather, crypto and stock data through API calls in Python
- · Developed a REST API for returning sports statistics and betting odds.
- · Implemented chenpost.com on an AWS S3 Bucket to allow clients explore and inquire on potential partnerships.

#### **DATA ENGINEER**

Vurteau / New York, NY / 2018-2019

- $\cdot$  Developed an API to distribute advertising creative data from S3 Bucket, with Cache to optimize server load usage. (Deployed on AWS EC2)
- Utilized pandas and numpy to perform data analysis and modeling on advertising campaigns performance for new insight.
- · Contributed Ideas to Vurteau's business Model that resulted in our initial \$500k funding.
- Provided research on various web technologies and costs that would help optimize the technological procedures. (AWS Media Tailor for ad insertion, S3 for Storage, EC2 for running Server)

#### **PRODUCT ENGINEER & CONTENT MANAGER**

Dahua Tech USA Inc. / Irvine, CA / 2015 - 2018

- Updated and maintained Dahuawiki.com to provide better technical support to the customers including adding YouTube tutorials with 7000 daily hits on website tracked through Google Analytics.
- · Hardware testing/support for clients including but not limited to NVRs, DVRs, IP Cameras, and Analog Cameras via Salesforce.

## **COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR**

Computer Science Learning Center, University of Memphis / Memphis, TN / 2014 - 2015

- · Helped students with coursework and checked coding errors
- · Taught & Mentored high school students with interests in Computer